William E. Moore papers, Inclusive: 1901-1979, undated, Bulk: 1902-1912, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
William E. Moore papers
Inclusive: 1901-1979, undated, Bulk: 1902-1912, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3185
Moore, William E., 1871 - 1946
5 document boxes.
The William E. Moore papers consist of letters and postcards, financial documents, and a photograph.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Born in Waco, Texas, on 1871 October 28 to Ernest Moore and Mary Costler, William E. Moore worked in Waco as a clerk for William T. Wallace in the 1880s, while living with his maternal grandparents. By the end of the century Moore had become an assistant undertaker for Fall & Puckett, a local funeral home in Waco. Later in life he became a funeral director.
On 1900 December 27, Moore married Myrtle Winn. They had one son, Walter Edwin Moore. Tragically, Myrtle died shortly after Walter was born. William lived about another forty-four years and eventually died on 1946 November 11 from heart complications at the age of seventy five. He was buried in Oakwood Cemetery in Waco.
Scope and Content
The William E. Moore papers begin in 1901 and end in 1979. The largest series in the collection is the Postcards series, consisting of more than 400 postcards. The collection also contains more than 100 letters written to William E. Moore between 1902 and 1918, financial documents dealing with property taxes and miscellaneous issues, and a photograph of Walter Edwin Moore, William E. Moore’s son.
Arrangement
The William E. Moore papers were somewhat organized prior to this finding aid. The letters had been separated from the postcards and some of the postcards were organized into categories. Most of those categories were preserved within the current arrangement.
Currently, the William E. Moore papers are arranged in four series: I. Correspondence, II. Postcards, III. Financial Documents, IV. Photographic Material.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3185. Acquired 1991-04-05
Related Resources
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. "William Ernest Moore." Memorial #56618189. Databases. Accessed 2013 June 21.
U. S. Bureau of the Census. 1910 United States Census. "James F. Winn," Port Arthur, Jefferson County, Texas. HeritageQuest Online. Accessed 2013 June 21.
General Directory of the City of Waco. Galveston: Morrison & Fourmy, 1888-1889.
General Directory of the City of Waco. Galveston: Morrison & Fourmy, 1898-1899.
Death Certificate for William Ernest Moore, 12 November 1946. Accessed 2013 June 21.
Index Terms
Places
Port Arthur (Tex.)
Subjects
History, 20th Century -- Texas.; Postcards.
Genres
Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographs.
- Correspondence, 1902-1918, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains more than 100 letters written to William E. Moore between 1902 and 1918. Most of the letters were written by Moore's mother-in-law, Ella J. Winn. This series is in average condition.
  - William E. Moore, 1902 April 7-26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 April 30-May 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 May 31-July 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 July 8-August 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 August 11-August 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 August 28-September 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 October 2-November 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - William E. Moore, 1902 November 7-December 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 January 5-February 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 February 10-February 23 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 March 1-March 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 March 20-April 14 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 April 17-May 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 May 17-July 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 July 6-July 19 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - William E. Moore, 1903 August 15-May 25 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - William E. Moore, 1904 June 1-October 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - William E. Moore, 1904 November 27-December 18 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - William E. Moore, 1905 January 26-February 16 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - William E. Moore, 1905 February 21-June 4 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - William E. Moore, 1905 June 8-December 25 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - William E. Moore, 1908 March 22-July 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - William E. Moore, 1915 July 20-July 30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - William E. Moore, 1917 August 3-1918 July 12, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General, 1902 December 28-1916 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Postcards, 1901-1979, undated; 2
  This is the largest series in the collection and contains more than 400 postcards, some of which are addressed to William E. Moore. This series is in average condition.
  - Holidays, 1905-1909 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Holidays, 1909-1913 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Holidays, 1913-1923, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sunday School, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Canada, 1939-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mexico, 1916-1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Paris, 1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Texas, 1906-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - General, 1901-1907 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General (1 of 2), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General (2 of 2), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - General (1 of 3), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - General (2 of 3), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - General (3 of 3), 1909 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General (1 of 2), 1910 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General (2 of 2), 1910 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General (1 of 2), 1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General (2 of 2), 1911 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General, 1913-1918 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General, 1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General, 1941-1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - General, 1951-1979, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General: Blank (1 of 4), undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General: Blank (2 of 4), undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - General: Blank (3 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General: Blank (4 of 4), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Financial Documents, 1901-1951, undated; 3
  This series contains financial documents dealing with property taxes and other financial issues. The series is in average condition.
  - Financial Documents: Tax Receipts, 1928-1932, 1951, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Financial Documents: General, 1901-1917 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Photographic Material, 1903; 4
  General condition: Good.
  This series contains a photograph of Walter Edwin Moore, the son of William E. Moore. At the time the photograph was taken, Walter was 14 months old. The item is in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photographic print
  - Photographic Material: Walter Edwin Moore, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 5)